# **KHAIRUL ISLAM**



#### CONTACT

- J 01707536945
- mdkhairul773@gmail.com
- 104 Central Road Dhaka 1205, Mymensingh, 2200 Bangladesh

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled and knowledgeable person with strong collaborative, time management and multitasking abilities. Committed to completing software development projects within budget and contract parameters. Experienced with Php, Laravel, JavaScript, React, Redux, Angular Js, jQuery, Nodejs, Express, MySQL and also knowledge of Codelgniter modern web application frameworks.

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML5 CSS Bootstrap
- PHP
- Laravel
- Codelgniter
- Nodejs Express Js
- MySQL
- Kenx Js
- Mongoose
- Prisma
- JavaScript React Redux Next Js
- jQuery Angular Js 1.8 cPanel
- GitHub GitLab
- REST APIs
- SOAP APIS
- Requirements analysis
- Database design

# ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Filling Station https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/lara vel7-starcorner
- POS Api With Laravel https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/pos -api
- Transport management Api With Express
  Js and Kenx Js
  https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/tran
  sport-server
- Agro poultry farm https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/kis an-agro
- Transport Management with codeigniter https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/tran sport
- Result System Hsc https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/res ult\_system\_hsc
- Bima / Shamity https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/sha mity
- News Paper https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/ne ws24bd
- Union porishod seba With Laravel 9 https://github.com/mdkhairul773islam/am arup

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER Oct 2023 - Current

Travelzoo Bangladesh Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- · Took technical responsibility across all stages and iterations of software development.
- · Completed multiple software development projects within assigned timelines and budgets.
- Performed front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- · Created interactive and dynamic applications tailored to client requirements.
- · Interacted with users to gather requirements and translated into visual design.
- Worked with modern web application frameworks like CodeIgniter, Laravel (Service provider, Service Container, Auth & Password, JWT, Events and Listeners, Basic Package Development, Middleware, ORM, Queues and Jobs, Email Sending, Livewire, Role and Permission) Node Js, React, Next Js, Redux, Redux Toolkit.
- · Developed clean, efficient code based on software application project scope.
- Worked with Soap and rest API like Saber API · Travelport API · Asmodeus API. SSL Commerce, Mobile SMS, Google Map, Google Chart, Gmail Mail Sender, Stripe, PayPal.
- · Works with the company's existing projects to find bugs and solve them by optimizing the code.
- Worked with Name chip cPanel, BDIX HOSTING.

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep 2020 - Sep 2023

Freelance IT Lab, Mymensingh, Bangladesh



- Work with engineers, developers of current applications and future applications related to the content management line of business
- Develop CMS components
- Manage multiple projects at a time Like POS software
- Education Software, Hospital and Diagnostics software, Bima software, Transport management software, Union Porisod software, ERP, CRM and many more as client requirements
- Create, document and execute software designs which may involve complicated workflows or multiple product areas with coding and beta testing
- · Works with R&D department to assist in planning and executing new product development
- · Work closely with other developers and product managers
- Delegate objectives to a team of coders to facilitate time frame and meet the common vision of the project
- Identifying and troubleshooting client issues then documenting solutions and development and QA procedures
- Providing guidance to other on-shore and off-shore developers
- · Project planning and database design with team leaders.

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER Dec 2019 - Aug 2020

SovWare, MFQJ+M7J, Dhaka

- Developed a HRM AND CRM application
- Where use multiple payment gateways
- Which application use for office and client management
- Developed a couple of web-based applications using
- Codeigniter, Bootstrap, jQuery, etc
- · We are building every project for the world's biggest marketplace of theme forest
- · Analysis of the client's requirement & project
- Working projects are Accounting software, Pos Software, printing service medium E-commerce website with payment gateway
- Debugged and modified E-Commerce software components.

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep 2016 - Nov 2019

Freelance IT Lab, Mymensingh, Bangladesh

- Performed front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Created interactive and dynamic applications tailored to client requirements.
- Improved UI for users, increases retention through intuitive workflows.
- Analysis the client's requirement & project.
- Developing web applications based on PHP frameworks Codelgniter, Laravel, JavaScript, Angular Js 1.8
- Build efficient, testable & reusable codes.
- · Modify existing code as needed.
- Executed and monitored standards for user interfaces page design and development
- Prepare Documentation: User Manual, Reference, and Changes.
- Perform other operational task based on "as and when required".
- I work like some software inventory management, hotel management, hospital management, student management, Results processing and so many types of software.

### **EDUCATION**

### BSC - COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Uttara University

### DIPLOMA - COMPUTER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

Mymensingh Institute Of Science And Technology, Mymensingh